[SPEAKER_01]: I'm here in Tampa talking to Tony Cuccinello in his lovely home.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is Thursday, January 3rd.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd like to have you just, if you would, start telling about your
[SPEAKER_01]: where you grew up, and now you happen to break into baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is the mic, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, Gene, I started in Long Island City, New York, which is part of New York City, and I played in semi-pro ball, and from there I had a tryout with the Syracuse Club of the International League.
[SPEAKER_00]: They brought me over to Jersey City to work out, and they liked what I did and what they saw, so they took me along to Baltimore and Newark,
[SPEAKER_00]: He finally handed me a contract and said, tell your daddy to sign it because at that time I was only 17 years old.
[SPEAKER_01]: That would have been about 19 or 24.
[SPEAKER_00]: 26, about June the 26th.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I did go away with them and went up to Syracuse and stayed there until about the first part of August.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then they phoned me out to the old New England League up at Lawrence, Massachusetts.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I finished out the season with them and had a fairly good year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I belonged to the St. Louis Cardinals at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they, they wanted, next year they wanted to send me to Topeka, Kansas.
[SPEAKER_00]: But not knowing where Topeka was, I didn't want to go, so I asked the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_00]: Branch Rickey was the big boss then.
[SPEAKER_00]: If he would farm me up again, up to Lawrence, Massachusetts in the New England League, which they did.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had a real good year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And from there they sent me out to Danville, Illinois in 1928.
[SPEAKER_00]: There I ran into a lot of boys that eventually went to the big leagues, like Paul Derringer, Alan Stout with the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_00]: George Puccinelli was with the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, God, there was a bunch of players right now.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't think of their names, but from that club, I would say 15 of the 20 players that we had went to the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the fall of that year, they sold me to the Cincinnati Club, which then operated at Columbus, Ohio.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, that was 1928.
[SPEAKER_00]: I finished the season in the last two or three weeks up at Columbus.
[SPEAKER_00]: and had a real good ending of the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the next year, they sent me a contract to play with the Columbus Baseball Club.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fortunately enough, I had a real good season.
[SPEAKER_00]: I came within a point or two of leading the league.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dusty Cook, who belonged to the Yankees at the time, and was with the St. Paul Club in the American Association, he and I tied for second and Bubbles Hargrave,
[SPEAKER_00]: an old Cincinnati catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Managing St. Paul, he won it by two points over both of us.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is in 31 now.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, that was in 29.
[SPEAKER_00]: So with that good year, the Cincinnati club took me up to the big club.
[SPEAKER_00]: I joined them right here in Tampa.
[SPEAKER_00]: They trained here in the spring of 1930.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let me interrupt this moment.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see how we're coming through here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your semi-pro ball there,
[SPEAKER_01]: Were there ball players in your family?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I was the first one that started in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Later on, my brother came along.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was with the Giants for a short period and belonged to the St. Louis Cardinals, played minor league ball, and then played with that Bushwick Club in Brooklyn, which was a real good semi-pro club.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then after that, I had two nephews, Sam Mealy, who managed Minnesota and also played, played with Cleveland, played with Chicago, played with the Red Sox, and he's now working with the Red Sox.
[SPEAKER_00]: And his brother, in fact, two brothers, Alfred and Freddy, played minor league ball around... Big Bud?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, there's no relative of Butch Mealy, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a boy that we know very well from New Jersey, but no relative at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: And although I'd say Sam is still in baseball yet, and my brother is scouting right now for the New York Yankees.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who signed you your first contract in the international league?
[SPEAKER_00]: Warren Giles, who later was the president of the National League.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in fact, that same year, Gabe Paul was just breaking in baseball, who now is the president of the Cleveland Baseball Club.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gabe lives here, right here in Tampa, and I get to see him quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did Warren Giles see you play then?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he took Bert Shotton's word for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bert Shotton was our manager at the time, plus the coaches that they had, whom I don't remember, and they handed me a contract at that time, I think it was about $400 a month, and to me that was a lot of money, 1926.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have your heart set on a big league career in baseball?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, I liked baseball so much that
[SPEAKER_00]: I wanted to try to see if I could make the Big Leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't have any idea that I could, which fortunate enough I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I did make it and I'm very happy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was your family happy about it too?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, at first my father wasn't very happy about it because he's an old timer from Italy and he thought that baseball was just passive fancy of some sort, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: So finally when I told him what I was going to get, well he agreed, he let me go and play and from there on I stayed in baseball all approximately, well I'd say from 26 to 1969 is when I really retired, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your father, did your father come over from Italy then?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he was here at the turn of the century, yes, when he first come over.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're originally from Naples, Italy and we had a little
[SPEAKER_00]: a village in Long Island that all the people from Naples would congregate in that one little spot and they were practically all relatives is what they were.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he or you ever get back to your native country?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I never have.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had brothers that went over and my father never went back, neither did my mother, but I've never been over there at all, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay, well then, you had this $400
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when I first started, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: This again is in the International League now?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I signed with the International League Club, but then when they found me to Lawrence of the New England League, that club up there only paid me $250 a month, but the Syracuse Club played the balance, which they had to do in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, we were through up there, I would say Labor Day is when the season was over, and the International League season went on to about the end of September, so I got another
[SPEAKER_00]: one or two checks until the end of their season.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay, now picking up with your first year with Cincinnati then.
[SPEAKER_01]: They trained down here?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, they trained here.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, where we trained and where we were housed is now the University of Tampa.
[SPEAKER_00]: It used to be the Tampa Bay Hotel.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was built by a railroad man called Phil Plante.
[SPEAKER_00]: He made a wonderful, wonderful building and beautiful rooms, large big
[SPEAKER_00]: big bedrooms, and we had it for two years, and then when we got out of there, we went to Orlando, and I was there, yeah, two years while I was there, and then the club moved to Orlando.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, in that second year, I was traded from the Cincinnati Club to the Brooklyn Club.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the Cincinnati manager, that Dan Howley?
[SPEAKER_00]: Dan Howley was the manager, came from St. Louis Browns,
[SPEAKER_00]: to take over for Sidney Weil in Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did you like Dan Howley?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Dan was a real nice man.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was more a fatherly type man.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he took a liking to me and I had problems starting out.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't hit too well at the start of the season, but then I got help from Harry Heilman, who was a great ball player with the Detroit club, and he helped me along with my hitting.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I didn't start doing it until about June of that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Heilman helped you?
[SPEAKER_01]: What did he tell you?
[SPEAKER_00]: He gave me confidence for one thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: He tried me to keep my eye on the ball, hit the ball back to the pitcher, hit the ball back to his man.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what he kept telling me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then later on, oh, after about 20 or 30 swings, he said, now hit the ball as far as second base, second base, second, and then later on, inter-center field, inter-center.
[SPEAKER_00]: The main thing was he wanted me to keep my eye on the ball, stay with it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And from there on, I was put in the lineup two days later and went on to hit, I believe, 312 or 314, something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's a great scorer.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I have heard from other players that when rookies come up, oftentimes the old-timers don't give them much help because they're going to take their jobs away, maybe, and they kind of, you know, they just put them down a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, here you're telling us about an old-timer who really helped you out, so you weren't jeopardizing his job at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he was an outfielder anyway, but I can remember Dan Howley.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't play too much in spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had Charlie Dressen, who was the third baseman, and Joe Strip,
[SPEAKER_00]: who was also a third baseman, first baseman, and we had George Kelly, Huey Crites, Horace Ford, and it was tough breaking in the lineup, but fortunately one of our first basemen got hurt and Dan Howley moved Joe Strip to first base and put me at third.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I can remember him saying to me, now look, I want you to look into the bench.
[SPEAKER_00]: Charlie Dressen will move you.
[SPEAKER_00]: I instructed Charlie to let you know whether to play back, play in, to the right or left, which I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Charlie was a great help to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because Charlie had played a few years in the major leagues and was on his way out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was great with young ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he did help me a great deal in moving me around.
[SPEAKER_01]: I understand 1930 was the year the averages were all the way up though, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, well I think the truth is that
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a lively ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the first year I was in the big leagues, but they all said that the ball was really, really lively and that even myself, I hit, oh, I don't know, eight or nine, ten home runs or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I hit some balls that were shots over the left field wall that I didn't believe I could hit a ball that far.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the ball had to be lively.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's when he was with the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Knocked in, I believe, 190 runs, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nobody will ever try that one.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, that's quite a season.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think the Phillies finished way down, and they had a team batting average of over 300.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, I believe they had a team batting average of 300.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then again, they had a ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a hitting paradise.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you like to hit there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yes, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when I had one of my biggest days in the major leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had six hits on six times of bat for nine innings.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your right hand hitter though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you hitting the right field?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, left field wasn't too far.
[SPEAKER_00]: At the power alleys about 345, 350 at the most.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right field was only about 275.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where Chuck Klein hit a lot of his home runs.
[SPEAKER_01]: He went over to Chicago and didn't hit so many home runs.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it was a little further over than Chicago.
[SPEAKER_01]: Any problems, any pitchers that gave you trouble in this first year?
[SPEAKER_00]: When I first started out, yes, they all gave me problems.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then later on, I got going.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit them all.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was only hitting about 210 up until June.
[SPEAKER_00]: As I said, I finished the season hitting 312.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to hit a great deal to do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you stay in the lineup at third base?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played second base a lot.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played third for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then they traded Huey Crites to New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: We got a first baseman infielder by the name of Crawford from the New York Giants, and then that's when Dan Howley moved me to second base, put Joe Strip at third base, and put Leo Durocher at shortstop.
[SPEAKER_00]: Leo hadn't played too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Horace Ford was at shortstop, and when they got rid of Huey Price, that was the end of Horace Ford also.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Leo was a real good help to me at second base also.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he just said, come over from the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_00]: He and Bob Musial, we had Bob Musial with us that year also.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'd say one thing about Leo.
[SPEAKER_00]: We finished up that year pretty good, made a lot of double plays.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, I hope we're together next year, which was 1931.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, we will set a double play record.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, something we did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Individual double play record and also a team double play record.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was 1931.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had 128 double plays that I, myself, participated in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it took, I imagine, 15, 20 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jackie Robinson in Brooklyn, later on, late in the 40s, was when he broke my record.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were these mostly feeling, or the outsets, I mean, or the assists, or both?
[SPEAKER_00]: Both.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had to start a double play or complete a double play.
[SPEAKER_00]: Leo was a real good shortstop, a real good glove man.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never did hit too much wherever he was, but even like when he was with the Yankees, they had such a great hitting team that they could afford to carry him.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I don't know, he got in some trouble over there and they just let him go and Dan took him on.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dan liked him very much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you find a big adjustment problem from 3rd over to 2nd or did you play 2nd before?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, well I had played 2nd base a great deal.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played a little 3rd base.
[SPEAKER_00]: 2nd base to me was more natural.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had started there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then 3rd base was what they call the old man's home over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just so you can knock down those line drives and have time to pick it up and throw the man out.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't no problem over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pretty strong arm you had to have.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well no, I didn't have too strong an arm.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had hurt my arm the year before I went to Syracuse.
[SPEAKER_00]: dislocated my elbow, but I got to throw the ball away quicker, like a lot like Robinson of the Baltimore Orioles.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't have too strong an arm, but as soon as I got the ball, I let it go.
[SPEAKER_00]: They knew it, and they'd get there in time to catch the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it made it a lot easier for me to play second base, because second base was more of a flip, not a long throw.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about the men coming down and stealing?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, once in a while you would, but you learn to get away, how to protect yourself, especially on double plays when they're coming down.
[SPEAKER_00]: The toughest part is when a fellow is stealing and a ground ball is in and you've got to make the double play.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now you know you've got to get out of there, otherwise he's going to upset you, which I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: They showed me how to do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to pivot on the inside and then make him get out of the way.
[SPEAKER_01]: You had a very good year in 1931, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, I believe it was 1931.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know I hit over 300.
[SPEAKER_01]: You played all 154 games.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played all the games.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, from when I first started in June, I believe I won about 400 or 500 games before I was out of a ball game.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, I was traded the next year to Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why were you traded?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Joe Strip and myself held out.
[SPEAKER_00]: We wanted a little more money, and of course, Mr. Weil had lost a lot of money, and he said he couldn't afford it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But after two years in the big leagues, I'd hit 312 and 315.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought I was entitled to more than what he was giving me at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we held out.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I was here in spring training in Tampa, Florida, when the deal was made with the Brooklyn Club, when Cincinnati got Babe Herman, Ernie Lombardi, and Wally Gilbert.
[SPEAKER_00]: and they gave Brooklyn, Clyde Sueforth, Joe Strip, and myself.
[SPEAKER_00]: At the time, Brooklyn Club was training at Clearwater, which is just about 18 miles across the bay here, and there was nothing for me to get over there, and Tampa, who was up in Orlando, those boys just rode up to Orlando and joined the club up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you feel about that trade?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I liked it very much because I was living in Long Island City at the time, and Brooklyn is on the south shore of Long Island, see, and it was just a matter of
[SPEAKER_00]: 15 or 20 miles from my house to the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was there four years, and I saved a lot of money by my expenses, living away from home.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about the ball club itself, playing with Brooklyn?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, very good.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, there was a good ball club at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I still believe that we should have won the pennant that first year over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a good ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went under the last road trip.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was about a 10-day road trip, leading by a game, and we came back off that road trip in third place.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were beaten by the Cardinals, then the Cubs knocked us out of the first place.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I believe the Cardinals went on to win.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a real good season.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had some pretty good ballplayers over there then.
[SPEAKER_01]: That'd be 32.
[SPEAKER_01]: That'd be the Cubs, wouldn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: The Cubs or was it the Cardinals?
[SPEAKER_00]: I know one of the two of them won it, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Glenn Wright with you, King?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, Glenn Wright was with us.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a real nice interview with him out in California.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, wonderful.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wonderful man, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess he was injured or something?
[SPEAKER_00]: He hurt his arm.
[SPEAKER_00]: He couldn't make the long throw from shortstop.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had Lonnie Fly and Mickey Finn, Gordon Slade.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was with us also.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about the man Wilbur Robinson?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wilbur went out that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Max Carey took the job.
[SPEAKER_00]: Max was only there one year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Our coach, Casey Stengel, who was one of Max's coaches at the time, he took over the following year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with Casey three years in Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was Max Carey?
[SPEAKER_00]: Max was a good manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a great believer in stealing bases and that sort of type of play.
[SPEAKER_00]: The way he was, he was fast, real quick, good outfielder, good hitter, and run bases.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I couldn't do it because my legs weren't that good.
[SPEAKER_00]: If my legs were real good, I don't believe I'd ever left the St. Louis Cardinals because they went in for speed.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was Ricky's number one priority, speed, run, run, run, run.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I couldn't do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wish I could and it would have helped me a great deal, I know.
[SPEAKER_01]: We're done here with Casey.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with Casey for three years, as I say.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with Max one year, Casey three years, and then I was traded to the Boston club.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you like Casey as a manager?
[SPEAKER_00]: Casey was a good man.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, he was better with the young fellas than he was with the old boys.
[SPEAKER_00]: The older boy, he figured, knew how to play ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd leave him alone, but the young fellas, he would talk to us for hours, hours, hours, and hours.
[SPEAKER_00]: Telling stories?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, not so much.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, tell us the baseball things and things we should try to do and learn to do and all like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he understand?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't talk that stingily at that time, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was more of a baseball man.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then, in fact, this funny thing, I was trained in Boston and McKechnie, Bill McKechnie was my manager up there for one year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thirty-six.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know something we got Casey Stengel back up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was back with him again for another four or five years, six years I believe.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's in the Hall of Fame because he's a great manager, but his team didn't do so well those years.
[SPEAKER_00]: He did well with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had players that the Yankees could do what he wanted them to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could say, go up and bunt, and they would bunt.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or go ahead and hit the right field, and they would hit the right field.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or he'd put you on your own.
[SPEAKER_00]: Guys he had like Tomacho and Hendricks and Berra.
[SPEAKER_00]: Those type of boys, he would just let them go.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was on their own.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you with the Dodgers when Kerry made his remark about being still in the league?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, that was 1934.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was asked that question.
[SPEAKER_00]: Someone asked him a question about, how about the Brooklyn Club?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, oh, why are they still in the league?
[SPEAKER_00]: But fortunately, that was 1934.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because it happened to be that the last two days of the season, Brooklyn was playing the Giants in the Polo Grounds.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the Giants needed one game for a tie.
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe the Cardinals were the team that year that won it, and we went in there and beat them two games and beat them out of the pennant.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did that, his saying, really fire you fellas up?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yeah, it did to a point that it made us feel bad, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then, of course, Casey had two or three meetings about that in particular, put it on our minds.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we went in there, yeah, we went in there like we were the world champs at those two games.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had finished, I believe, sixth or seventh in an eight-club league.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your average fell off a little bit those years, but how'd you feel about that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the first year in Boston I hit 300.
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe I hit 307, 308, something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I went down, I went down a little bit up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boston was a tough ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a big, big field and we played right alongside of the Charles River up there near Cambridge Pass, you know, right across from where Harvard is.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the wind was always blowing in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had to learn to hit the right field.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was more of a full hitter at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: So after that, it started helping me again to spray my balls around, not try to go for the long ball or hit the ball hard anyway.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just go for singles, which helped my average quite a bit after that.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Ebbets Field as a hitter, as a ballpark?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, no, Ebbets Field was good to hit at.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, at that time, 1930, I got my first home run in Ebbets Field against Adolph Lukey, but the ball bounced into the stands.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, that time was a home run.
[SPEAKER_00]: And about two or three years later, they changed the ruling of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That had made it an automatic double.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had to hit the ball into the stands in order to get the home run.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was Mungo like?
[SPEAKER_00]: Mungo was a real good, I wouldn't say a real good pitcher, but he could throw.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could throw hard.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could overpower you.
[SPEAKER_00]: He developed a good curveball that made him a real, real, real tough pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he wasn't the kind that could spot the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just overpowered it with his speed and good curve.
[SPEAKER_01]: Control?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, he had pretty good control.
[SPEAKER_01]: He really had that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he had a big wind up.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd cock his leg way up in the air.
[SPEAKER_00]: And look, by the time he brought it down, it looked like he was right on top of home plate.
[SPEAKER_01]: The way pictures now have no wind in them.
[SPEAKER_01]: You wonder back in the old days, people like Feller and Vance... We had Vance was on our club in Brooklyn that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's the one who used to wear that cut-up shirt, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: He used to cut his shirt up so when he went around, that would flare like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: They finally stopped him from doing that, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Dazzy Vance, he was quite a picture.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he was on his way out because Dazzy had come up to the big leagues late in his career.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he still pitched, I believe, when he was 38 or 39 years old.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why did he come up so late?
[SPEAKER_00]: I really don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know they say that he come up around the age of 29, 30, somewhere around there.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I first seen him in 1930, he could throw hard.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in fact, before I started playing regularly again, I had started, and Dan took me out of the lineup.
[SPEAKER_00]: One day, Dazzy was pitching against us, and they had us beat something like 7-2 or 7-1.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Howley said, how would you like to hit against Vance?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, sure, I'd like to hit against him, just to see how hard he throws.
[SPEAKER_00]: He did.
[SPEAKER_00]: He put me in the pinch hit in the eighth inning of the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'll say one thing, he could throw hard.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did he do?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I don't exactly remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I don't.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about another officer?
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was catching with the Dodgers?
[SPEAKER_00]: Lopez.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hank Deberry, who used to catch Vance, and then he would catch one or two of the other pitchers, and Lopez would catch the majority of the pitchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then, I would say around May or June of that 1930, Al was put in and he was the regular catcher from there on.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was his first year then?
[SPEAKER_01]: His first full year, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: 1930.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then he stayed there 1930.
[SPEAKER_00]: He left with me 1935.
[SPEAKER_00]: the fall of 35 to go to Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went up there together.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he was a good receiver.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, the first two years he hit real, real good, but he caught, I believe the first year he caught something like 145 games out of, and it just tired him out.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just, he got so that he couldn't hardly swing the bat.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a 300 year the first year he played, but then from there on he went down, oh, around 260, 65, somewhere there, but he caught
[SPEAKER_00]: He caught for a long time.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, he caught 18 years in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wanted to talk to him, but I couldn't find his name in the phone book.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess he's not listed.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I don't believe he is.
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was your Cincinnati catcher again?
[SPEAKER_00]: At that time, we had Val Pacinic, Johnny Gooch, and a young boy by the name of Welder.
[SPEAKER_00]: Clyde Tukvoth was with us and another young kid, we had ball catchers there for quite a while, Asby Johnson, they finally shipped him out to the minor leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: He won't use the name of Asby, but his name was Asby Johnson.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about batting against Carl Hubble?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not that I want to brag or anything, but I could hit Carl good.
[SPEAKER_00]: At that particular time, I was strictly a low-ball hitter, and Carl was a low-ball pitcher with his screwball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd pitch it in and out, in and out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Luckily, I would say, I bet I hit 300 over him.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were some guys in the league that weren't as good a pitcher as him and used to get me out more than Carl did.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I had good success against Hubbell.
[SPEAKER_00]: The fellow at New York in particular gave me trouble.
[SPEAKER_00]: was Leroy Pommaly.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, gee, Leroy, he could throw the ball hard, but that's the thing, you were a little leery of getting sculled, you know, and at that time, in that particular time, we never wore helmets at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: No helmets.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says in his career he hit five batters in the head, minor in the majors, and he was no good after that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it got to bother him a lot, I know.
[SPEAKER_00]: One year in the big leagues he hit
[SPEAKER_00]: three fellas in the arm and broke two or three of their wrists.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't mean to do it, just that wild.
[SPEAKER_00]: He tried to throw strikes, but the ball would get away from him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's pretty well crippled up now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, I imagine after so many years of baseball and injuries that you get, my knees bother me a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've been hit there a couple of times on these, around second base.
[SPEAKER_01]: Breaking up a double play.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Schumacher was real good.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was an overhand sinker ball pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: He came up in 1930, I believe from St. Louis College up in New York State somewhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: A real good competitor, a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: So was Freddie Fitzsimmons on the ball club at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were three great pitchers.
[SPEAKER_01]: He just died last night.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, I know he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I read that in the sporting news.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were out there in California two years ago and I got to talk to him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was your, what was your line-up up there in Boston?
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember when you went up there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I don't remember the particular line-up, but I can, well, see, Lopez caught, we had Baxter Jordan at first base, I played second base, we had Billy Urbanski, and then after he, Eddie Miller, remember, later went to Cincinnati, Eddie was with us, and Pinky Whitney at third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lethfield, Adel, Howley, Wally Berger, and Gene... Moore.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gene Moore was our right fielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pitches, we had Danny McFadden, Fetty, Turner.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah, that was the year they broke in.
[SPEAKER_00]: They broke in, they won both 20 games, I believe, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were really late.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they were, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Johnny, I don't believe John, come up until 31 or 32.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then he pitched until he was almost 40.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then later on he became a relief pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was an interesting team.
[SPEAKER_00]: Danny McFadden was one of our great pitchers up there, too, that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: He came from the Red Sox to the Yankees to the Boston Braves.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wore glasses, didn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, yes, real thick ones.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was one of the first ones to do that.
[SPEAKER_01]: There were a couple of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, there was, like, George Teposa, the infielder with the Cardinals, wore glasses.
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe one of the Hill boys, Common Hill, wore glasses.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, he said he missed the 1927 season when the Pirates won the pennant.
[SPEAKER_01]: He won 22 games, and he says he could have won 23 because he's pitching the last game was ahead by a couple of runs with two out in the fifth inning, just when he would get credit for the game if he got one more man out.
[SPEAKER_01]: He made a violent pitch and knocked his glasses off and stepped off.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't get the victory.
[SPEAKER_01]: He laughed about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wonder how it must have been.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, they do it quite often now.
[SPEAKER_00]: We even got catchers now wearing glasses, which was a rarity.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ever see a catcher with glasses back then?
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd think, you know, afraid you're going to break them and all like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever get hit in the head badly?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, a couple of times I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were you serious?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it wasn't serious.
[SPEAKER_00]: One hurt me a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: It hit me in the back of the neck.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's the thing of losing the ball, that's the thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Especially in the Cubs ballpark, before they changed it, they used to have a low center field and all the people in the summertime with the white shirts would sit out there and the ball was thrown out of the way and you couldn't pick it up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had some hard throwers there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Twice I could hit there and once in Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: They used to have a low center field, and all the people in the summertime with the white shirts would sit out there, and the ball was thrown out of the way, and you couldn't pick it up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had some hard throwers there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Twice I got hit there, and once in Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_01]: Glancing blows?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, one was a glancing blow over the top of the head.
[SPEAKER_00]: The one that hurt me a little bit was one right back of the neck, that I did finally have a little calcification up there
[SPEAKER_00]: They were going to take out and finally said, it didn't bother me, just let it alone.
[SPEAKER_00]: It took me about a week before I was able to start playing again.
[SPEAKER_01]: None of them knocked you out though?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, momentarily, that's about all, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Stay in the game?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, the second one, no, I didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got out.
[SPEAKER_00]: The first one I stayed.
[SPEAKER_01]: If they'd had helmets then, would you have thought they were a good idea?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it was a good idea.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think maybe it would have helped a bunch of us.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember
[SPEAKER_00]: Bucky Wallace hitting Billy Jurgis in the Polo Grounds just above the ear.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now the helmet would have helped him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember Mungo hitting a boy by the name of Marshall with the New York Giants in the head.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wasn't thrown at him, but just the ball got away from him and hit him, and that was the end of that poor boy's career.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there were several incidents.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now maybe that boy in Cleveland that was killed, remember Chapman?
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe he might have been saved, of course, if they had helmets at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you hear some of the old-timers kind of look down their noses at helmets.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's something almost unmanly.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I mean, I guess they're thinking maybe they shouldn't be wearing them, but I'm glad to see the boys wearing them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I see a lot of times boys getting hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Glancing blows up, which helps a lot.
[SPEAKER_00]: It stops concussions and things of that sort.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you a little gun-shy if you got back there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, for a game or two.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they take you out and give you batting practice and help you.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I know before I went back, I can't remember who was the manager at the time, but he said, I want you to go up there and take batting practice without knowing what's being pitched.
[SPEAKER_00]: They get me back in stride of hitting.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that helps you going back into the game, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: Got to go right back in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: You've got to make up your mind.
[SPEAKER_00]: You've got to do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And once you get one game under your belt, then you're all right again, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about the old days?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was no easier boy to hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now this is a boy that good fastball used to bear into a right-hander.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's like what they said, he slung the ball, as he used to say.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a slingshot artist, you know, and the ball would bear into a right-hand hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of times he started in a little too closely and you better get out of the way, but he was rapid.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was really, really fast.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot faster than his brother Paul.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he talk during the game?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he'd lob or do anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, one day in Brooklyn, he came in our clubhouse and conducted Casey Stengel's meeting.
[SPEAKER_00]: Told him exactly how he was going to pitch to us, and pitched a three-hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd the players react to that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they didn't mind.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the comical sort of a guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, a lot of fun.
[SPEAKER_00]: O'Doul used to get a big kick out of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: O'Doul used to con him a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he always said, gee, that lefty's a good guy, but lefty'd always come up with a couple of hits off him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's another character, Lucky O'Doul.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have any O'Doul stories?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, well, all I know is that we played with this in Brooklyn, and he always wore that green suit, that Irish suit, and Lucky was a real good hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had hurt his arm.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a pitcher before going to the outfield, and hurt his arm, and he couldn't throw very well.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had good legs.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could get to a ball, he'd hold on to it, but when it was too deep, somebody had to go out to second base for the first base, and had to go out and help him throw that ball in.
[SPEAKER_01]: Somebody said that Old Duo was in a town in about ten minutes and he could have run for mayor or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a very comical man and a very, very nice man.
[SPEAKER_01]: This thing here doesn't tell you when it's over, so I've got to keep my eye on it.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about the umpires?
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill was one of the best umpires we had in the major leagues at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, there are real good young umpires now or even later on after Bill, but we did have a bunch of older type like Moran.
[SPEAKER_00]: Remember Charlie Moran from Center College in Kentucky?
[SPEAKER_00]: Charlie was a good man, Bill Crammond, Cy Riggler was another big tall man.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, they had a lot of the old timers and they were just getting through when I was breaking in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then the younger boys started coming in like Larry Getz.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was Ensley still around?
[SPEAKER_00]: Who?
[SPEAKER_01]: Bill Ensley.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he was in the American League at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I started in the National League.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I can't think of exactly who.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know that Bay Pinelli was around.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, Ernie Quigley was still in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he retired, I believe, and went back to Kansas to teach.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a teacher of some sort, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get thrown out of any games?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not too many.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got thrown out of one game, not being my fault.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now there's another man I just thought about.
[SPEAKER_00]: The man that threw me out of the game, Beans Rarity.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a little problem with beans.
[SPEAKER_00]: The club had a little problem with beans at St. Louis one day.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had left the dugout to go in the back.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when I come back up a hit or two later, I went up to the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I questioned one of his pitches that he called a strike on me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And right without saying another word, he said I was out of the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, why?
[SPEAKER_00]: I just asked you about the pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, well, that was the reason he had told everybody on the bench.
[SPEAKER_00]: The next one squawks about any kind of pitches out of the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was out.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know anything about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then he apologized to me later, which I told him that I wasn't on the bench when he come over to let everybody know what's going to happen, and I was the guilty one.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you thrown out of any others for a better reason?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't even remember being thrown out of any more games, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you argue much?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: They knew.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't squawk too much, but if I had a squawk come, they knew something was radically wrong.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were good to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, they'd say later on, like if I tagged the man, they thought I didn't tag him, they'd come back and say, did you really tag the man?
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'd say, yes, I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I tagged him on the side or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they would believe you.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were real, real good.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know later on I went to coaching, coaching third base, and two or three times I've seen fellows make swipes at my men and hit them, tag them, and the umpires would call them safe.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they weren't in position at the time to see the tag, but two or three years later they'd come over and ask you, was he tagged or not?
[SPEAKER_00]: I wouldn't lie to them, tell them the truth.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, he was tagged, and I think they liked me for it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you think they do a pretty good job overall?
[SPEAKER_00]: They do a lot better job now because they only cover one base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now they got four umpires.
[SPEAKER_00]: Years ago we had only two for a long time and that made it a little tough.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now the umpire at home plate had to coil the balls down both lines.
[SPEAKER_00]: fair or foul, which is a tough thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: You take curving balls 340, 50 feet down the line, it's tough to sell it, whether it hit the line, off the line, fair or foul, which is real, real bad.
[SPEAKER_00]: But now, as they say, World Series, they have six, two down each line, makes it a lot easier.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think it's a lot nicer, a lot better.
[SPEAKER_00]: It makes the game better, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're on top of players.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if you notice, a lot of these instant replays, they don't make many mistakes.
[SPEAKER_00]: They don't make many mistakes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Back in the real old days, they had just one umpire.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he used to be behind the plate, and then he'd walk out behind the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I remember that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they'd tell stories about players cutting from first strike to third strike.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I don't remember those times very much, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: No wonder the umpires took a beating when they literally threw bottles at him and things like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: You played in Columbus then.
[SPEAKER_01]: The old Neal Park, was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Neal Park, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I stayed at the Neal house, too, there, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then there was another little hotel that I moved later on out called St. Francis, out North High Street, going out toward the university, out that way.
[SPEAKER_00]: Didn't the players stay in the same place?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, not at home, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're on our own at home, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's at your expense.
[SPEAKER_00]: When they go on the road, then they house them at one hotel, see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I can remember there was a soldier's home out near the ballpark when we played out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fort Hayes?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right, it was right near Fort Hayes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there was a soldier's home across the street from the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course now, it was a year or two after that they built the new ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: When did the Cardinals get there?
[SPEAKER_00]: The Cardinals went in about 1930, I believe.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when Cincinnati owned Columbus 28-29.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they got rid of it and the Cardinals came in there after that.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, we were the Columbus veterans at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then they became the Columbus Redbirds.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, the vets.
[SPEAKER_00]: After the veterans in the home there.
[SPEAKER_01]: How big a park was that?
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a pretty good sized ballpark, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe there was a brewery back in left field.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, it ran about 360 feet, 355, something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who managed that club?
[SPEAKER_00]: Nemo Lebo.
[SPEAKER_00]: Old Nemo Lebo.
[SPEAKER_00]: You remember Joe Carr, the old football man?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was president of the club, he run the club, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you know Nick Collins?
[SPEAKER_00]: Nick was one of our players, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He later went on to manage the association, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He did his home runs as well.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he went up with me in Cincinnati, Silas Johnson.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I can't think of some of the other boys.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oscar Eckert went up, pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nick never could quite cut it when they were... No, I mean, he used to hit .340, .350 in the minor leagues all year, but then he come up odd.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Whether he had a nuclear complex or...
[SPEAKER_01]: I think he was up with the Yankees, too, in the mid-twenties, just at the time Earl Combs came up, and they already had Neusman Roof.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So it was just bad timing.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think that's what we agreed upon when I started with him, that he just, every chance he got seemed to be at a moment when there were
[SPEAKER_01]: pretty tough competition.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I do remember one incident very well in the Polo Grounds when Nick was playing with us in Cincinnati in the early part of 1930.
[SPEAKER_00]: I happened to be at second base and Travis Jackson, Stoney Jackson, the shortstop, and there was a pause, a minute or two, something had happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Cullum was the
[SPEAKER_00]: the hitter, and he said to me, watch how they pitch this fella.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now he's been around here for, he had three or four tries already in the big leagues and never made it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'll start pitches around his letters and he'll keep going up and he'll keep missing them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And sure enough, that's the way they pitched him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he wouldn't lay off the ball, he'd swing at the ball and invariably miss it.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, he was more of a ball, he did the ball more of a low ball hitter, about waist high, but they would start by the letters and keep going up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd keep off and let the pitch, and that's exactly what they did.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Joe Hauser?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever play with him or against him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe Hauser?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, in the association.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was with Milwaukee, I believe, when I was with Columbus.
[SPEAKER_00]: Great home run hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, yes, Joe.
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember very well the fact that then he hit about 55, 56.
[SPEAKER_01]: He has a record of hitting over 60 home runs in two different leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had 63 with Baltimore in 1930 and 69 with Minneapolis in 1938.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, it was up there somewhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know it was in an association, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: They claimed he had a
[SPEAKER_01]: kind of a band box to hit up in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever see Nicollet Park?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what it was called at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I played in that ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a really short ballpark, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: You could hit line drives and hit the center field wall.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had this, he was a left-hand hitter, and his right field at that time, I would say, oh, about 260 feet, about 260, but the fence was up about, oh, 25, 30 feet.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he used to loft the ball, and he'd hit
[SPEAKER_00]: over that 30-40 feet.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a little irritated.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was up with the athletics for a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a real good major league career ahead of him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He twisted each knee.
[SPEAKER_01]: Once he got his left knee and that finished him for a while, then he got back and the other knee went.
[SPEAKER_01]: And very routine plays.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd really rented his major league for him, but he could still hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe he went to managing after a little while, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he did briefly.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm not sure he was too happy in that role.
[SPEAKER_00]: But no, I knew Joe very well, and I'd say playing against him, he seemed to be a real, real nice fella, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: I spent a whole day with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He lives up in Sheboygan.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, way up in north Wisconsin up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a real great guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a wonderful man.
[SPEAKER_01]: I enjoy talking with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever meet Luke Boone?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not Ike, Lute.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, you mean the infielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was with us at Columbus.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was wondering if you knew him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, in 1928 he was our shortstop.
[SPEAKER_00]: We got a boy by the name of Fritz Nikolai.
[SPEAKER_00]: came in and replaced him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Emmett McCann was one of our players.
[SPEAKER_00]: D.B.
[SPEAKER_00]: Foss was the third baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, and how about the right fielder that was up in the big leagues, came down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ernie Neese?
[SPEAKER_00]: Bernie Neese.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Bernie Neese was in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Luke Boone was up in Pittsburgh now.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's still in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's about 86.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he's got to be a lot...
[SPEAKER_00]: I know he's a lot older than I am, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Danny was a... wasn't it called Danny Boone?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember him very, very well.
[SPEAKER_01]: Played a lot with St. Paul and he played some of Louisville.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, he was a lot older than I.
[SPEAKER_00]: When I joined the club, I was just about 19, 20 years old, something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were you with the 28th St. Paul's Club?
[SPEAKER_00]: 28?
[SPEAKER_00]: 28, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've got a big picture of that team.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I'm on it, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I didn't realize that.
[SPEAKER_01]: You got it framed and like... Yeah, 28.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, now, it's according to when they took the picture, now.
[SPEAKER_00]: If they took it late in the season, I was on it, but...
[SPEAKER_00]: In 28, I joined them from Danville, Illinois, in a 3-I.
[SPEAKER_00]: Went over to Indianapolis, where they were playing there, and... What's the name?
[SPEAKER_00]: Nebo Lebo put me right in the second ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got there while the first game was going on.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, get in uniform, and I went in and played the second game of the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: stay there two or three more days and move on to Columbus.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played approximately two weeks.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were in Indianapolis though?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, against Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember Eddie Sicking?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sicking?
[SPEAKER_01]: Second baseman?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah, yes, yes, yeah, very well, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Freddie Haney was the third baseman that year over there, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Amy Leedy, remember Amy Leedy?
[SPEAKER_00]: Clyde Barnhart.
[SPEAKER_01]: Those are old timers.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was in Hagerstown, Maryland.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was just there last summer.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe Sprintz, the catcher, and the two brothers lived in Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_00]: One went up to the Cincinnati as a pitcher and one was a catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Riddle, Elmer Riddle, John Riddle, they played there in Indianapolis also.
[SPEAKER_01]: You meet a lot of players once you've been down.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got a picture inside that I'll show you a little later on.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I'd like to show you my little room that I fixed up myself.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was ailing at the time and he used to play a lot of golf at the Westchester Country Club that was very, very hilly.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hilly, rocky and all like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the babe got so that he couldn't walk those hills anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he used to come out of Bayside, Long Island, which was about, oh, five minutes from my home.
[SPEAKER_00]: and play out there that it was all flat and he could play.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we used to have a lot of fun playing with him or behind him or in front of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then we'd come in and we'd sit down and he would tell us some stories about his...
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, the one time that I played with him in 1945, I almost led the American League in hitting.
[SPEAKER_00]: I lost the last day of the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: George Stern was beating me out.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll never forget, Babe, after we got in that day, after the game was over, he said, Hey, I understand that you almost led the American League in hitting.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said the American League must have gone far back and you almost led it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Babe was a real good fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, he never used your name at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, see we played against him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went up to the Boston Braves when I was at Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then a year or two later when we were traded, they released him at Boston and he came down to Brooklyn as a coach.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he used to give on exhibitions and hitting between double-headers and all that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd hit for 10 minutes at a time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you think he would have made a manager?
[SPEAKER_01]: He always wanted a manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, but I think the New York Yankees offered him a job at Newark.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I think he wanted to manage the Yankees themselves.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, it's hard to say if he'd have been a good manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can't tell.
[SPEAKER_01]: You'd have to see.
[SPEAKER_01]: Good players don't always make good managers.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's true.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, well, you went in 1939.
[SPEAKER_01]: You played 81 games.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you injured that year?
[SPEAKER_01]: What, 39?
[SPEAKER_01]: 39.
[SPEAKER_01]: With Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh no, 1939.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I think that was the year that they brought up, Casey brought up Sidney Sispy from Hartford, Connecticut.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he asked me if I would work with the kid.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, don't you worry.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said that you'll have a job here as a player or as a player coach.
[SPEAKER_00]: You work with this kid.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I believe that was the year that I didn't play too many games.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, and that was the year that I hurt my knee also.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, that same year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they brought him up and he filled in while I was hurt.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was out
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, practically two months.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dick Bartel at the Cubs at that time run into me at second base and wrenched my knee.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was no break of the bones, but he tore my internal lateral ligament, which is why I was told.
[SPEAKER_00]: It took me about two months before I got back in the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now I remember very well.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was the incident.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was this a stolen base attempt?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it was a double play thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was running on a plane.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got there in time and hit me like on a football block and hit me right across my knee.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it was more of a block.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was trying to break up the double play and that's what happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then you could do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can't do it no more, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now they call both runners out.
[SPEAKER_00]: You go out of your way to get an infielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you can slide at an infielder and either touch the base with your hands or your feet, it's alright.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can still knock him down.
[SPEAKER_00]: break up the double play, but if you go out of your way and you cannot reach the bed, they'll call both men out, the hitter and also the runner.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you get any scraps about people fighting you like that?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we've had little scraps and all like that, but you go in and try to break it up and all like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm a little too small.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't want to try to get in any of those battles with some of those big guys.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then in 40, you went over to the Giants.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, that was around June or July.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess it was the cut-down time or the ending of the trading season.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Boston Club was in bad shape at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: They traded both Lopez and myself.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lopez to Pittsburgh and I went to New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was more of a part-time player over in New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had Billy Jurgis, Lighthead, Mellot even played third base some in that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Played 88 games with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I mean, I know I just filled in.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't pinch Ted quite a bit, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you like Bill Terry?
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill was a good man.
[SPEAKER_00]: A real good baseball man.
[SPEAKER_00]: A good, strict manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was more like the McGraw type of manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was the one that I could have stayed with the Giants the following year, but he asked me if I would like to take the Jersey City club as a manager for him, or come back and be a utility player.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the money was going to be the same thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I said, well, let me chance this.
[SPEAKER_00]: This manager's job.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went over there for that one year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I went back to the Boston Club.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were a playing manager?
[SPEAKER_00]: Playing manager until they sent me Mickey Wittig, the second baseman, and I took myself out off the list and put him on.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played for about a month.
[SPEAKER_01]: They played in Roosevelt Stadium, the one that was built by
[SPEAKER_00]: during the WPA projects.
[SPEAKER_00]: Opening day, we had 62,000 tickets sold.
[SPEAKER_00]: The property holds about 25,000 people.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that was the time Mayor Hague would go all around the city, and if he handed you five tickets, you better take them and just pay for them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he'd let you get rid of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had 62,100-some-odd paid admissions.
[SPEAKER_01]: for that day.
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember that very, very well.
[SPEAKER_01]: I've seen pictures of the ballpark that day.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd only seated about 25,000.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that an old ballpark?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh no, at that time it was new.
[SPEAKER_00]: They used to play what they call old west side ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a real, I would say like a semi-pro ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: Seated maybe 5,000 or 6,000 people and fences were about ready to fall down and then they built the Roosevelt Stadium.
[SPEAKER_01]: quite a rivalry there between Newark and New Jersey.
[SPEAKER_00]: There are two clubs that are owned by the New York ball clubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: One the Giants and one the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the Yankees had a tremendous, powerful club over in Newark, which they had in Kansas City also at the time and had one at Binghamton, New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: In Virginia they had another one.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a bunch of good ball players.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, they were one of the first clubs or teams that
[SPEAKER_00]: Had the farm system, started the farm system.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cardinals, the New York Yankees, and then the Brooklyn Dodgers were the ones built when Mr. Rickey went over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Cardinals would have a team in each AAA league?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: One in each AA, or I guess they just had AA.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, see, now I can remember being with the Cardinals in 1928, and we had five clubs in Danville, Illinois.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had batting cages that would go out, put you in a hit, it would be in a batting cage.
[SPEAKER_00]: and they'd have maybe six of them around the whole field, and then all balls would be hitting like in that straight center field.
[SPEAKER_00]: No one could be hurt because they had nets along the side.
[SPEAKER_00]: The pitchers, the only one that had to worry about, they had no nets in front of the pitcher, and you would hit balls out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody would be hitting balls in the center field.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then it would, after about an hour or so, they'd call halt and go out and pick up these balls again and start over again.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Mr. Rickey, he's the first one to come in with the numbers, you know, on the back.
[SPEAKER_00]: back in the uniforms.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never knew our names, he just used your number.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mine was 155 in Danville.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd say 155, but he knew who I was.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd say 155, had my name alongside it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd say, tell a picture you want to see fastballs, fastballs.
[SPEAKER_00]: And finally say curveball, curveball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he would grade you
[SPEAKER_00]: I think Sam Breeden was the owner, but he might have been a part owner of the club, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you think of Branch Rickey?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a good baseball man, a real, real good baseball man.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got to meet him maybe just one time, and I didn't know too much about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Talked to the contractor.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd sell you a bill of goods, and then you'd go back and think he was right.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't make you feel good about taking cut in pay.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he had a lot of those fellas at the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_00]: Even in the early 30s, other clubs were paying them in $10,000, $8,000, $7,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had fellas playing over there for $3,000, $2,500, even like the Dean boys when they first come up.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't make hardly any money after all.
[SPEAKER_00]: What he'd do, he'd sign you for a three-year contract and graduate you $1,000 a year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then maybe the second year, you might have an outstanding year where you should have got
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe a $5,000 raise, but he had you to that contract.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was a good baseball man.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the first one.
[SPEAKER_00]: He believed in speed.
[SPEAKER_00]: Speed was the first thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hitting last.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hitting was last.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: They got you out of the Cardinal system.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a break because they had so many players in the farm.
[SPEAKER_01]: You might have had a tough time working your way up to the top.
[SPEAKER_00]: Another fellow was with us, Rip Collins.
[SPEAKER_00]: Remember Rip Collins, one of the Cardinal men, the Cubs?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was with us at hand the last year, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, now later on, they got rid of Rip, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: He weeded out everybody that couldn't run.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jimmy Jordan went to Brooklyn when I went.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were in the same organization, rather.
[SPEAKER_00]: He sold him, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: He couldn't run.
[SPEAKER_00]: Couldn't feel a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: He stayed around and played more of a relief man is what he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Utility man, but a good player, good everyday player.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he got rid of everybody.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just couldn't run.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd line us up, hold a second baseman, you had to run.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I would probably be the last one running, or finishing rather.
[SPEAKER_01]: Speed is important, but other things are too.
[SPEAKER_00]: He figured speed first, fielding next, throwing and then hitting.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know later on when I run the Tampa Club down here in 1947, Clyde Sooper was now working for Branch Rickey in Brooklyn, and he and another man used to go all over the United States running schools, and that's the way they used to start.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd have a regular form, say running first, and you'd take all the outfielders together, run them, and put down their speed.
[SPEAKER_00]: Run good, fast,
[SPEAKER_00]: can't run, second baseman, and so on down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they'd weed out the ones that couldn't run, whether they could hit or not, but took the ones that could run.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they had some baseball ability, and then they'd have games, like inter-squad games among themselves, and they would pick out the clean.
[SPEAKER_00]: Say three or four fellows here in Tampa, then they might go to St. Pete, pick up two more there, then go up to Georgia somewhere, pick up three more there.
[SPEAKER_00]: At the end of the year, they've maybe got 100 ball players, and maybe out of that 100, five might make it.
[SPEAKER_00]: See?
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had real good ballplayers, in fact, good fellows that could run, really run.
[SPEAKER_01]: In those days, did you fellows think much about the color barrier, or there being no blacks playing?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, in fact, no one would bring it up.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a funny thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I can remember
[SPEAKER_00]: My son was born in the fall of 1945, and we had a lot of problems with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: So in 1946, I had a job with Casey Stengel out of Oakland, California, as a player manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, as a player coach, rather.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I couldn't make it because I was living in Long Island, being out in California, 3,000 miles away.
[SPEAKER_00]: My wife was a nervous wreck on account of the boy being ill.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I stayed out of baseball in 1946 and played with the Bushwick Club.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, the Bushwick Club played all the
[SPEAKER_00]: colored teams prior to them getting in the big leagues, like the Kansas City Monarchs, the Baltimore Elites, the Crawford Club from Pittsburgh, they had two clubs, the Homestead Grays was another club, the Buckeyes were there, Kansas City Monarchs, Satchel Paige, and I hit against all those fellas, pitches and played against them before they got back into the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, they didn't get into the big leagues around 48.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you feel about them?
[SPEAKER_01]: They were pretty good?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, they were good ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had some tough guys.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had fellas on our club, and I was through as a major league ball player at the time, but my brother played.
[SPEAKER_00]: We played minor league ball, little major league ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had two pitches from the Philadelphia Phillies that were up a year or two.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gene Hermensky played with the Brooklyn Dodgers.
[SPEAKER_00]: He played with us.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a catcher that used to be with the Pittsburgh Pirates.
[SPEAKER_00]: A boy was with the New York Giants, first baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, we played four games a week.
[SPEAKER_00]: Four games a year.
[SPEAKER_00]: One Wednesday, Friday, and a doubleheader Sunday.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was a tough league.
[SPEAKER_00]: We played all the colored clubs, and they were real tough players.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there any feeling about it, playing with them or something like that?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, not whatsoever.
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, around New York City at the time, we played with them and played against them.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was nothing at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was just the major leagues that didn't accept them at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, and then when...
[SPEAKER_00]: Dobey, I guess Dobey was... Robinson.
[SPEAKER_00]: Robinson with Brooklyn and Dobey with the Cleveland Club.
[SPEAKER_00]: They started, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they played against both those boys.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Luke Easter, Satchel Paige, Suitcase Simpson, a boy by the name of Troop, a catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Quincy Troop.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's Quincy Troop, right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you do it during those 30 years in hitting?
[SPEAKER_00]: I only played maybe 20 or 25 games.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I took myself out of the lineup.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was tough trying to manage.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was my first venture as a manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was trying to play and manage.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had no coaches on the club.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to do everything myself, which was a tough job.
[SPEAKER_00]: Even the small class A clubs now have a coach or two.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like here Tampa has two of them and they're in class A baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the manager has a lot of help, but I didn't have it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to pick out one of my older pitchers to help me around with this and that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what made it real rough for me and then sort of discouraged me a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: I figured, gee, this is triple-A ball and I didn't even have a coach to help me.
[SPEAKER_01]: When the club was owned by the Giants, would there be a kind of a business manager assigned to Jersey City?
[SPEAKER_00]: a general manager, he was also our road secretary.
[SPEAKER_00]: He would go with us and take care of the building of the road, make arrangements for us.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was one of Mr. Terry's men.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the thing is, another thing too, that I got orders every day from New York who to play.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have to report after every game?
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd call me every day.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mr. Terry would call me every day.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't care too much about winning, is what he said, but he wanted to worry about developing players.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had three or four pitchers that looked real good, Huey East, Reuben Fisher, Lou Henshaw that used to be with the Cubs, Roy Henshaw, and one or two of them went up and relieved for a boy by the name of Huey East.
[SPEAKER_00]: real good pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sid Gordon was a shortstop at the time that I tried to play with him to make him a shortstop and eventually I had to tell Terry that I didn't think he could make it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a little shy around the base, tagging men, missing men, and defensively he wasn't that great on ground balls, but became a great outfielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: Had a good arm.
[SPEAKER_00]: Terry said, what do you think?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I'd like to use him in right field and stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's supposed to go first to third, you know, and
[SPEAKER_00]: because they usually go from Whitefield and say keep on going and going.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd throw them out because he could throw.
[SPEAKER_00]: What an arm.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he stayed with the Giants for a while and traded them to Boston I believe.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you get over to Boston for 42?
[SPEAKER_01]: What happened after the 41?
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the year that Mr. Terry and Stoneman got on the outs and Mellott was named manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Bill still was the head of the farm system and his friend Poncho Schneider,
[SPEAKER_00]: He wanted to take care of him, so he asked me if I wanted to go back to the major leagues again.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, I already had a contract signed.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, your contract will be taken care of.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I'll send you back to Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, which was all right with me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he gave Poncho the job at Jersey City Metal.
[SPEAKER_00]: How could he send you to Boston?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he made a deal with Bob Quinn, and I accepted the deal.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because I already had signed a contract for 41, I believe it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: 41 or 42.
[SPEAKER_01]: So your contract went with you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: They sell you your contract.
[SPEAKER_00]: They don't sell you.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, they buy your contract.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the idea.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I went back and stayed 42 and 3.
[SPEAKER_00]: 43, I went to the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_00]: What about World War II?
[SPEAKER_00]: Were you battling?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: My arches were bad.
[SPEAKER_00]: My throat was bad and I was deferred.
[SPEAKER_00]: Remember, that was the year they kept baseball going.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, the three years they kept baseball going.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was more of all fellows that were 4Fs that played.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was your manager in Boston in 1942?
[SPEAKER_00]: Stengel was still the manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: The one year we had Bob Coleman and George Kelly as co-managers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Remember when Casey was hit by a taxi cab?
[SPEAKER_01]: In Boston?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was going home to his hotel, walked over, got off the sidewalk, and a cab hit him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was laid up for a good two or three months.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Bob Coleman and George Kelly, who were both coaches, they were selected as co-managers for most of that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Casey came back the latter part of the year on crutches and finished the year out.
[SPEAKER_01]: He played only 40 games there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, that was the year that Sistey took over second base.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was with him the year before, and then I stayed with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I did a lot of coaching with him, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: When the year that he was here, when I wasn't playing, I'd coach third base in Georgia, go to first base and call him to be on the bench.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what got me interested in the coaching career, that I liked it so much.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you're helping fellas play, watch the mistakes they make, and try to help them out here and there, and especially the infielders, anyway.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your first stint with Boston, was Bob Smith still up there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, the pitcher?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, Bob was there, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bob used to be an infield originally.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was talking to him down in Atlanta.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Bob was with us.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, this deal to Chicago, that was in... 1943, I believe I went there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They released me just to cut down time and White Sox happened to be in town playing the Boston Red Sox when the Braves went west.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I went over to Dykes and asked Jimmy if he would need some help as an infield either.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hadn't played too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I'd have to get in shape because honestly, I haven't played but a few games.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, look, I'll tell you what, do come out and work out with us that in a day or two, I'm going to lose Don Colloway, the infield, if he's going into service.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I'll take you along with me and I'll give you a pay retractive as of today.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I worked out with him and he let me go home to New York, which they were coming down to New York to play the Yankees, pick up some clothes and work out with him again.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to Baltimore with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know him, but Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went from there to Washington with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And finally, I think the next town that I went to, he gave me a contract and dated it back to what it called, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the funny thing, the first day that I got to play,
[SPEAKER_00]: I pulled my leg.
[SPEAKER_00]: My legs weren't in shape to play.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he took care of me and I finished out the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a fair year the next year, but in 1945 I had a real good year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I should have led the league by 20 points.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was now 38 years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was right near there anyway.
[SPEAKER_00]: I lost 15 or 20 points the last month.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was up around 35-40 and I wound up 308.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Sternweiss beat me on 308.5, made it 309.
[SPEAKER_00]: But in New York, what they did in New York, they changed an error to a hit so he could win it, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know that, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was the Boston Riders.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were playing the Boston Red Sox at the time when the Boston Riders were pulling for me.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I had been in Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had the two-point lead, and I was rained out a doubleheader the last day of the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they played one in New York.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a two-point lead, and he came up with three hits to beat me out.
[SPEAKER_01]: They changed one of those?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they changed one of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they said he had already been on first base, went to second, went to third base when
[SPEAKER_00]: The official score said the games in Chicago rained out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sternweiss had a chance to leave the league.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, change that every two weeks.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then he still had to get another one the last time, about which he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Everything went well that year, though.
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe the last month it didn't go so well.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dykes helped me a great deal.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just tired out at the end of the year.
[SPEAKER_00]: At that particular time, you had to be in 100 ballgames or I believe 400 times at bat to qualify.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to play the last time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't even believe I was a 410 or 412.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had to play, I had to play.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Jimmy was good to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: If I'd go up and get two hits in a ballgame, he would take me out.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wouldn't let me finish the whole ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd give the rest of me up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe a day, say maybe a fellow was going to pitch and a fellow had come back from the service,
[SPEAKER_00]: He put Joe Orrengo in there, he wouldn't put me in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wanted me to lead the league.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, Jimmy was a third baseman, and no third baseman up until that time had led the league, the American League.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had a chance to do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: After that, George Kell did it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the first one.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you were playing third then?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was playing third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I couldn't play second, I couldn't move around.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was 38 years old, at least 38 years old.
[SPEAKER_01]: They say third base is the old folks.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I didn't do too bad.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got in good shape.
[SPEAKER_00]: At 45, I got in good shape.
[SPEAKER_00]: We trained at French Lake Springs, Indiana, and I took those baths.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had baths there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I took them, and we had a run in snow.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they had a bridle path there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They pushed the snow aside, and I got in real good shape.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact,
[SPEAKER_00]: The lightest I've ever been in my baseball career is when I started that season.
[SPEAKER_00]: 168.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to play 72, 74.
[SPEAKER_00]: And right from the first day, got two hits, two hits, four hits, three hits.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was 380 or 40 or 50 for a long time during that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I say, last month I was leading the league by 335.
[SPEAKER_00]: The closest one was, it wasn't even Sternweiss, I think it was Wally Moses, was hitting 310 or 312.
[SPEAKER_00]: See?
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I just faded out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it's a funny thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mrs. Comiskey had called me in two weeks before the season was closed.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, the boys are coming back.
[SPEAKER_00]: Collaway was coming back, and all the boys were coming back.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Peace Treaty was signed with Japan, all of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, I enjoyed what you've done for us.
[SPEAKER_00]: She gave me a little bonus, a $500 bonus, but gave me my release two weeks before the season was over, ending at the last day of the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had in my pocket my release, and I could have led the league.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I had quit in 1941 in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you planning to play in 1946?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wanted me out in case he had a player coach.
[SPEAKER_00]: In other words, maybe fill in here, pinch hit occasionally or something like that, be on the active list in case he wanted me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think it was after 1945.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I got my release.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wasn't going to play.
[SPEAKER_01]: But before you got that, you're having this good year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was struggling, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just figured it was going to be over, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when Casey wanted me to go out to be a player, a coach.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, pinch hit, play when you can play a little bit of game here and there, which I figured, well, then maybe I could do that until the kid took the sick on me and I didn't do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I played about 90 games with the Bushwicks, but... Oh, that's a big schedule, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah, 90 ballgames, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So did you work that year at home?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I just stayed at home.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played 90 games with the Bushwicks.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a game over in Waterbury, Connecticut and another game over in Orange, New Jersey.
[SPEAKER_00]: Semi-pro.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to pick up $125, $140 plus my salary that I was getting with the Bushwicks.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was wondering if they paid you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, definitely.
[SPEAKER_00]: That year I must have made $7,500 or $8,000 and stayed at home.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was your salary your last few years in the big time?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I can't remember exactly.
[SPEAKER_00]: I would run around $12,000, $14,000 at that time, which was big.
[SPEAKER_00]: I made more money as a coach than I did as a player.
[SPEAKER_01]: So $47,000 then.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you do that year?
[SPEAKER_01]: I played with the Bush with $47,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the first year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought that was $46,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: I came right down here to manage Tampa.
[SPEAKER_01]: What organization is this now?
[SPEAKER_00]: It was owned by an individual, Tom Spagola.
[SPEAKER_00]: Privately owned, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you come across here?
[SPEAKER_00]: Al Lopez is the one who called me.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wanted to know if I wanted to get back to baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said yes, I'd like to get back because now the kid is on his way, feeling good.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I've got a chance for you to manage this club now if you want it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I figured, well, let me go take it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was in the Florida International League.
[SPEAKER_00]: Havana was in the league at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I figured, well, I'll take it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the salary wasn't too bad.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he gave me a chance that I would get so much.
[SPEAKER_00]: If we drew so many people, he'd give me some money.
[SPEAKER_00]: If we sold money, he'd give me 10% of the sale of players, which I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I made a little money that way, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had a good year with the club.
[SPEAKER_00]: We played 154 games with a 15-player limit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Can you imagine?
[SPEAKER_00]: I had five pitches.
[SPEAKER_00]: and won 104 ballgames and finished second.
[SPEAKER_00]: Havana beat me out.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you like playing on Cuba there?
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't play there, of course.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had to go down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was quite a rivalry, Tampa and Cuba.
[SPEAKER_00]: When we played here, we'd have 10,000 or 12,000 people in the stadium and only seated probably about five.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd put seats on the field.
[SPEAKER_00]: When we'd go to Havana, we'd draw 25,000 people.
[SPEAKER_00]: Really good.
[SPEAKER_00]: All night games?
[SPEAKER_00]: All Nikes, all Nikes, and Grand Stadium.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got a big stadium down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no, we had more than one state stadium.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fort Lauderdale, Miami Beach was bad.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were in the league at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: St. Pete, Lakeland, West Palm Beach, Miami, Miami Beach, Havana.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a good league.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was Class C league, but it was better than the C league.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot better.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's like the Yankees in 54.
[SPEAKER_00]: They won 103.
[SPEAKER_00]: We won 111.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with Cleveland then.
[SPEAKER_00]: I grew up in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with them in 54.
[SPEAKER_00]: We lost four straight to the Giants.
[SPEAKER_00]: The funny part, we had to wait for a playoff.
[SPEAKER_00]: Don't you remember?
[SPEAKER_00]: The Giants were in the playoff that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had one dependent.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's see, Greenberg was one of our owners and someone else.
[SPEAKER_00]: He asked the Washington Senator Club if they would stay over and play us ball games to keep the club in competition and the Washington Club would refuse it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we had to play in a squad games to try to keep in shape and then we would enter the series cold as could be.
[SPEAKER_00]: They beat us with Dusty Rose hitting what they called in New York those Chinese home runs.
[SPEAKER_00]: The first one he beat Lemon in the 10th inning with a 250-foot home run.
[SPEAKER_00]: It just fell in the right field.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a shame.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then the early pitch to three or four hitters in the second game, he got beat.
[SPEAKER_00]: We never, Mike Garcia lost the one next one and then Lemon come back again.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were given Mr. Lopez help not starting Bob Feller in the series.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I think Al used his best pitches and he's trying to win and trying to win.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had Lemon win Garcia.
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe all three of them won 20 ballgames.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Feller was more of a spot pitcher, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Outerman had won 15, and he had spotted, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: And Al would figure his pitching staff accordingly.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd go into New York City against Rashie, Lopez, and Reynolds, and those guys, Al would have Lemon, Wynne, and Garcia to go against them, and he'd pitch Feller in town ahead, or Outerman in town ahead, and maybe Narleski, pitch him four or five innings, bring in Marcy four or five innings, to go into New York with a good pitching staff, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Oscar Malone with the team?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, Oscar wasn't with us then.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oscar was with Woodrow.
[SPEAKER_00]: Woodrow was mayor then.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oscar went to St. Louis with Lou.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Browns were in the league then.
[SPEAKER_01]: What years were you with Lopez and Cleveland?
[SPEAKER_00]: Fifty-one, two, three, four, five, I believe.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that really a solid team?
[SPEAKER_01]: They had a great record.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, good record.
[SPEAKER_00]: Great pitching, good hitting, lousy defense.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we scored enough runs.
[SPEAKER_00]: We scored a lot of runs.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, the pitching kept the other clubs from scoring, and we had enough power to get a lot of runs for them to win.
[SPEAKER_00]: Our defense was terrible.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a poor fielding club and a poor running club.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we just had good power, real good power on the club, and good pitching, terrific pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a member, Marcy Nolesky,
[SPEAKER_00]: 8th and 9th innings, bring those kids in, it was all over.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Rustin never did much after that, did he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Boston had some good years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well, no, Rustin went through until he went to AL, and he said to AL, he wanted to become a starter and hurt his arm.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, now he started throwing hard for more than three innings.
[SPEAKER_00]: All he'd go would be about three innings was the limit, and he'd strike anybody out of three innings.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can remember one time in the Yankee Stadium with Mantle and Pat, and the base was loaded.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were one run to the good, the ninth inning, and three straight fastballs had struck him out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, base hit, we're done.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Al, he spoke to Al, and Al said, look, here's what I want you to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I want you to ram back and throw strikes and throw as hard as you can.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's what the kid did, threw strikes, three of them right in a row, struck Mickey out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: What do you think about this?
[SPEAKER_01]: a new pitching strategy of having starters, middle, long relievers, and short relievers.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: You get a complete game, it's really an unusual thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I see it now quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm out of the major leagues since 1969, but I know they're doing that a lot in the big leagues now.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got a long starter.
[SPEAKER_00]: As soon as the first starter gets out, they got a long relief man comes in, then another man for me, then the cleanup man at the back.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, years ago, I can remember, there was no relief pitchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the only time you'd bring a pitcher in is about the eighth inning or ninth inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd pinch hit for the pitcher and bring in another fellow to finish the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they weren't even called relief pitchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: They just were another pitcher on your ballclub.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they'd come in and finish the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then it got to be later on.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I think Mr. Casey Stengel was the first one who started that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he started the Pukun system, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right against left, left against right, and all of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: What do you think of that?
[SPEAKER_00]: I think it hurt a lot of ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Especially a lot of left-hand hitters that never hit left-handed pitches.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because they never faced that many.
[SPEAKER_00]: A good hitter would hit right or left-handed regardless.
[SPEAKER_01]: I suppose there is an advantage in that curveball coming in from their own side.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you see them every day, how about the right-handers that face the right-hand pitchers every day?
[SPEAKER_00]: They got to hit them and they did, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember guys like Bill Terry, Babe Herman, Lefty O'Doul, Mel Ott, they hit against everybody, right and left-handed, and they hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there was a lot of guys before them like Lou Gehrig and Babe Ruth.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ty Cobb didn't care how they threw.
[SPEAKER_00]: He hit 400.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sure, see, I mean, it didn't matter much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because at that time, they didn't think about alternating back and forth.
[SPEAKER_00]: And if I say pinch hit, there'd be maybe one pinch hit in a game for the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: It'd be the 8th or 9th, and that's the way it'd go.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pitches could hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were a lot of pitchers in baseball that had good records, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: George Hewley, I think, is more proud of his hitting than his pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was good, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember George very well.
[SPEAKER_00]: Red Lucas we had in Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember him, and there was a boy by the name of Brame in Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: They used to use him as a pinch hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a couple of guys.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lemon was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, Bob started as an infield outfielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sure.
[SPEAKER_01]: Have any Dave Herman recollections?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, see, I didn't play with Dave.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played against him.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were traded for one another.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd say a lot of stories, but they say a lot of those things that
[SPEAKER_00]: You read in the paper that they did not happen.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like he being hit on the head with a fly ball, I never did see it.
[SPEAKER_00]: They kid a lot about it, but they say it never did happen.
[SPEAKER_00]: He did, they said, one time lost the ball in the sun, got in on his shoulder, but it was due to the sun that he lost the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: At that time, very few guys wore glasses, sunglasses.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where did they play their first night ball?
[SPEAKER_00]: In Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: Remember?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with Brooklyn.
[SPEAKER_00]: Philly played the first game.
[SPEAKER_00]: At that time, each club played only one game.
[SPEAKER_01]: We came in later on.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had pretty good lights at the time compared to some of the minor league lights that I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was afraid to go up to the plate, I'll be honest with you.
[SPEAKER_00]: that they were real, and how these kids played with some of these lights, I do not know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I feel sorry for them.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't have lights though while you were still in the minor league?
[SPEAKER_01]: I think they came in about the next year or so, after you came up to Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, well they didn't have, they had, once in a while, we played an exhibition game in Indianapolis, had these portable lights, and Bob Musial was on our club, Bob used to hit infield for us a little bit, and he used to hit balls up in the air, over the lights, and you couldn't see the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd wait until they'd come down where it got into the lights, and then it was too late to catch it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But there was portable lights generated on the side.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess the first minor league lights were pretty dim.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had to be, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had to be.
[SPEAKER_00]: How'd you travel around in the minor leagues?
[SPEAKER_00]: In Danville in the 3-I was buses.
[SPEAKER_00]: At the New England League we had three cars.
[SPEAKER_00]: One was a big locomotive, it would carry about seven or eight boys, and the other two cars would bring the club and the manager with us, and maybe a man to take care of the reservations and all like that, hotels and things of that sort.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd have maybe two road trips going up to Maine.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd stay up there for two or three days, play Portland, Lewis, Auburn, and then down to Manchester, New Hampshire, things like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That would be the only time probably we'd stay overnight, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: You'd fly around by jet?
[SPEAKER_00]: And then, of course, when I got to the Association, we traveled by train, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: Which to me, that was a great thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had big leagues, trained in big leagues, too, until late.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't remember what year it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I wasn't a player when we were flying.
[SPEAKER_00]: I became a coach.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was coaching when we started flying.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about those long train rides from Boston to St. Louis?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, we've had that, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Twenty-four hours it took us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, sir.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did you do all that time?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you'd go to bed and you'd lay down and read.
[SPEAKER_00]: play cards.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, during the war years, one of those 43 or 44, we took a train ride from St. Louis by coach to Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, by Pullman of Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then get out of the Pullman, got in coaches, all the way into Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: They needed the Pullman again to go someplace else and probably carry troops is what they were doing at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was tough.
[SPEAKER_00]: Traveling was tough at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Even in the three-eye league, we traveled by bus.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had to go from Danville, Illinois, over to Quincy, Illinois, right across the whole state.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's over near Iowa, in that area.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have a regular driver?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: The bus was owned by the club, but they had a regular driver.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some of the players in the minor league, you used to tell them how they had to drive cars and buses.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here, right here in this league, I had Chet Covington, a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: They used to give them an extra dollar a day meal money for the bus, to drive the bus.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd go to Miami or Miami Beach, and we'd go to Hibernia, but we'd leave the bus there.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd go over and fly back and pick up the bus, and we'd make a move to Fort Lauderdale, West Palm Beach, and they had it all on there.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you do in the off season during all your years?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Outside of the war years that I went into a defense plant, I had three years.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was an iron worker at the time making these gun shields.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know much about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was easy for me.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a whole rivets and nuts that my boss would make up these bolts and all like that, and that was my job.
[SPEAKER_00]: But other than that, I didn't do any work at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you do a lot of hunting?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to do a little bit when I first got married, and then I got away from it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to go up to Connecticut away.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had friends up there, a lot of birds and all of that, mostly birds.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was your home still in Long Island?
[SPEAKER_00]: At that time, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm down here now about 20 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: During your baseball period, most of you stayed there?
[SPEAKER_00]: All along, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: During the war, I went to Queens College in Greece.
[SPEAKER_00]: I lived just about a block away.
[SPEAKER_00]: I lived in Flushing, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: One of the professors bought my house.
[SPEAKER_00]: I lived in the back end of Flushing where the Old World's Fair used to be.
[SPEAKER_00]: So my daughter, my daughter didn't apply.
[SPEAKER_00]: She took the exam at Queens College and she had something like 84, 85 was passed.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, it was a city-owned college and if somebody took it, they wouldn't accept it.
[SPEAKER_01]: catch it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He handled the game pretty well.